[cheerful music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[excited chatter]
[兴奋的喋喋不休]
- It's too high.
I can't!
- 太高了。
我不能！
- Cannonball!
Ohh!
- 炮弹！
哦！
- Now you've got water wings.
Try them.
- 现在你有了水翼。
尝试一下。
Hmm?
Huh?
唔？
啊？
- Ahh-ahh-ahh!
- 啊啊啊啊！
- Marco!
- 马可！
- Eeh.
- Marco?
- 呃。
- 马可？
- No, I'm Joshua.
- Okay, bye.
- 不，我是约书亚。
- 好的，再见。
Marco.
马可.
- Polo.
- 波罗。
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
Marco!
马可！
[whistle blows]
[哨声响起]
Shady Shoals residents,
out of the pool.
谢迪浅滩居民，
从池子里出来。
- I pooped.
- Come along, Mortimer.
- 我拉屎了。
- 来吧，莫蒂默。
- Huh?
Oh.
- 啊？
哦。
[elephant trumpets]
Huh?
[大象喇叭]
啊？
I'm covered in wrinkles.
我满身皱纹。
- Oh, we all are, dear.
- 哦，我们都是，亲爱的。
I call them oldie foldies.
我称它们为老折叠机。
[strains]
[菌株]
Hurry, Mortimer.
快点，莫蒂默。
Shady Shoals is serving
prune ice cream today.
Shady Shoals 正在服务
今天修剪冰淇淋。
- Dah!
Ice cream, oh, oh!
- 啊！
冰淇淋啊啊啊！
Wait for me!
等我！
- Marco!
- 马可！
Marco!
- [grumbles]
马可！
- [抱怨]
- Marco?
- Yeah, I'm-a Marco!
- 马可？
- 是的，我是 - 马可！
What do you want?
- Oh, I don't want you.
你想要什么？
- 哦，我不需要你。
I want Patrick.
我想要帕特里克。
- Then stop
a-yellin' my name!
- 然后停下来
喊-喊我的名字！
- Ugh.
[softly] Marco.
- 呃。
[轻声]马可。
- Attention, everyone.
- 大家注意了。
We found a lost
elderly gentleman
我们找到了丢失的
老先生
who goes by the name
of Mortimer.
谁叫这个名字
莫蒂默的。
Can anyone claim him?
有人可以认领他吗？
[tires squeal]
[轮胎吱吱声]
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- Come on, let's move it!
- 来吧，让我们移动它！
I want prune ice cream.
我想要西梅冰淇淋。
all: Ohh.
全体：哦。
[straining]
[紧张]
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
- Mortimer, ice cream time.
- 莫蒂默，冰淇淋时间到了。
- Ahh!
[panting]
- 啊！
[气喘吁吁]
Ahh.
啊。
[gulps, belches]
[吞咽，打嗝]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Brain freeze!
大脑冻结！
- Clear!
- 清除！
Clear!
清除！
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Oh. Ah.
- 哦。啊。
Brain food.
健脑食品。
[gentle music]
[轻柔的音乐]
- Eh?
- 呃？
- Ehh?
- Eh.
[straining]
- 呃。
[紧张]
Oh?
哦？
[laughter]
[笑声]
[straining]
Eh?
[紧张]
呃？
[laughter]
[笑声]
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[flat-lines]
[平线]
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
- Got you!
- 明白了！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Marco!
- 马可！
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
- Marco!
- 马可！
- You!
- 你！
What I tell youse
about-a yellin' my name?
我告诉你什么
关于——喊我的名字？
- Ahh!
I-I don't remember.
- 啊！
我-我不记得了。
Um, sometimes
it helps me to remember
嗯，有时
它帮助我记住
if I go into a trance.
如果我进入恍惚状态。
I'm seeing a small farmhouse
painted white.
我看到一座小农舍
漆成白色。
Does that have
any significance to you?
那有没有
对你来说有什么意义吗？
- My parents had
a white farmhouse.
- 我的父母有
一座白色的农舍。
- What's this?
A baby has been born.
- 这是什么？
一个婴儿出生了。
A boy.
There is much happiness.
一个男孩。
有很多幸福。
- That's-a me.
I was-a born there.
- 那是-一个我。
我出生在那里。
- They are about
to name the boy...
- 他们是关于
给男孩取名...
- Marco.
They named him Marco.
- 马可。
他们给他起名叫马可。
It's Marco.
Marco!
是马可。
马可！
- Polo.
- 波罗。
- Ahh! If I catch anyone
a-yellin' my name again,
- 啊！如果我抓到任何人
再次呼喊我的名字，
I'm-a gonna hurt them.
我会伤害他们。
- Whoo-hoo!
[screaming]
- 呼呼！
[尖叫]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Marco.
- Polo.
- 马可。
- 波罗。
- Ah-ha-ha!
Found you!
- 啊哈哈哈！
找到你了！
Now it's your turn
to call Marco.
现在轮到你了
给马可打电话。
- Do I know you,
young man?
- 我认识你吗
年轻人？
- Patrick, it's me.
Remember?
- 帕特里克，是我。
记住？
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
海底♪
- I don't know.
A wizard?
- 我不知道。
巫师？
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
Ehh.
呃。
- SpongeBob SquarePants!
- 海绵宝宝！
♪ ♪
- [laughs]
The one and only.
- [笑]
唯一的。
Okay, now it's your turn
to call Marco Polo.
好的，现在轮到你了
给马可波罗打电话。
- Whoa-oh, I can't do that.
- 哇哦，我做不到。
I'm all wrinkled now.
我现在满脸皱纹了。
I do old stuff.
我做旧事。
- Old stuff?
Like what?
- 老东西？
比如什么？
- Check it out.
- 一探究竟。
This is called doddering.
这就是所谓的老态龙钟。
[straining]
[紧张]
Oh, here's another thing
I do now.
哦，这是另一件事
我现在就这么做了。
It's called gumming.
这就是所谓的涂胶。
[lips smacking]
[咂嘴]
Neat, huh?
整洁吧？
Now this part's really fun.
现在这部分真的很有趣。
It's called complaining.
这叫抱怨。
These kids today,
they don't know diddly squat.
今天的这些孩子，
他们不知道蹲着。
- Ah. Hmm.
- 啊。唔。
- Wow, Patrick,
those are all great things,
- 哇，帕特里克，
这些都是伟大的事情，
but wouldn't you rather
go jelly fishing?
但你不想
去钓鱼吗？
- Ohh!
No, that hurts.
- 哦！
不，那很痛。
- We could be sand castles.
- 我们可以是沙堡。
- It's not
structurally sound.
- 不是
结构健全。
- Well, how 'bout
blowing bubbles?
- 嗯，怎么样
吹泡泡？
Nothing bad about a bubble.
泡沫没什么不好的。
- Ooh.
- 哦。
[explodes]
[爆炸]
Are you trying
to kill me, son?
你在尝试吗
儿子，要杀我吗？
- No, I just think
we should act our age.
- 不，我只是觉得
我们应该表现出适合我们年龄的行为。
Remember when
we used to look forward
记得什么时候
我们曾经期待
to rainy days
and building cushion forts?
到下雨天
并建造缓冲堡垒？
- These days,
I only look forward
- 这些天，
我只期待
to my final exit.
到我最后的出口。
- Oh, he was too young.
- 哦，他太年轻了。
- No, I wasn't!
- 不，我没有！
all: No, he wasn't.
We are not young.
所有人：不，他不是。
我们不年轻了。
- Come on, people.
- 来吧，人们。
Just 'cause you're old doesn't
mean you're rotting fish.
只是因为你老了
意味着你的鱼正在腐烂。
You're still vital,
full of life.
你依然充满活力
充满生机。
Fresh.
新鲜的。
- Fresh, you say?
- 你说新鲜？
Ahh.
啊。
- [straining]
- [紧张]
Okay, you young-at-hearters,
好吧，你们这些年轻的心，
today you are gonna climb
that tree.
今天你要攀登
那棵树。
[all grumbling]
[大家都在抱怨]
Yes, yes, that's right!
是的，是的，没错！
Put those flabby arms to use.
让那些松弛的手臂派上用场。
Laugh at your lumbago.
Cackle at your cataracts.
笑你的腰痛。
嘲笑你的白内障。
[all straining, grumbling]
[全都紧张、抱怨]
- Is it nap time yet?
- 午睡时间到了吗？
- Nope! It's time
for the dance party!
- 没有！是时候了
为了舞会！
Everybody on board.
每个人都在船上。
[all muttering]
[大家嘀咕]
Are you ready to get down?
你准备好下来了吗？
- Yeah.
[all snoring]
- 是的。
[全都打呼噜]
- No, not like that.
Like this!
- 不，不是那样的。
像这样！
[ragtime music]
[拉格泰姆音乐]
- Now--now--now--
Now you're talking.
- 现在--现在--现在--
现在你在说话了。
- Now let's kick it up
a hundred notches.
- 现在让我们开始吧
一百个凹口。
[dance music]
Yeah!
[舞曲]
是啊！
[all grumbling]
- Oh, what's happening?
[大家都在抱怨]
- 哦，发生了什么事？
[flat-line]
[平线]
- Oh, clear!
- 噢，清楚了！
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[laughs]
[笑]
- Isn't it great
to get outdoors
- 这不是很棒吗
到户外去
with the fresh air
and sunshine?
和新鲜空气
和阳光？
- Stop this rug!
- 停止这块地毯！
Bunny Buns.
兔子包子。
all: Bunny Buns!
Bunny Buns!
全体：兔子包子！
兔子包子！
- Bunny Buns?
That's a good idea.
- 兔子面包？
这是个好主意。
Nothing makes people
feel young
没有什么能让人
感觉年轻
like arcade games,
grease and sugar.
像街机游戏，
油脂和糖。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[children chattering, laughing]
[孩子们叽叽喳喳、大笑]
- This is fun!
- 这很有趣！
♪ ♪
- You're coming in too fast
on the bridge
- 你来得太快了
在桥上
and you're blowing clams.
你在吹蛤蜊。
- Ah.
Ohh!
- 啊。
哦！
[crying]
[哭泣]
- Now that's
what I call jazz.
- 现在就是这样
我称之为爵士乐。
- Ha ha. So sorry.
- 哈哈。很抱歉。
Let me just take this.
让我拿着这个。
- [grumbles]
Hmm.
- [抱怨]
嗯。
- I can help you with that.
- 我可以帮你。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Eww.
- Hey!
呃。
- 嘿！
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- [gurgling]
- [咯咯声]
- Old people, behave!
- Whoa!
——老人家，守规矩！
- 哇！
[dinging]
[叮叮]
23 skidoo!
23 滑雪！
- Oh.
[groans]
- 哦。
[呻吟]
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
I'm drowning.
[straining]
我快淹死了。
[紧张]
- I'm coming, Patrick!
- 我来了，帕特里克！
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
- Thanks, old-timer.
- Oh, you're welcome.
- 谢谢，老前辈。
- 哦，不客气。
What, who you calling
old-timer?
什么，你打电话给谁
老前辈？
Whoa.
哇哦。
Where have the years gone?
岁月都去哪儿了？
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
- I'm losing steam.
- 我失去了动力。
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Wait, hey, man.
- 等等，嘿，伙计。
Don't make a scene in front
of all my old friends.
不要在前面大吵大闹
我所有的老朋友。
Oh.
Ohh.
哦。
Now I can't dodder.
现在我不能再犹豫了。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
Here you go, friend.
给你，朋友。
[flat-lines]
Huh?
[平线]
啊？
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Got you!
- 明白了！
[laughter]
[笑声]
- You got me again.
- 你又抓住了我。
- Marco.
- Polo.
- 马可。
- 波罗。
- Marco!
- Oh, that's it!
- 马可！
- 哦，就是这样！
I said I was-a gonna
clobber the next-a person
我说我是-将会
打击下一个人
what-a calls my name!
什么叫我的名字！
- No one clobbers Clarabelle!
- 没有人能打败克拉拉贝尔！
[engine revs, tires screech]
[发动机转速、轮胎尖叫声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Oh, Marco?
- 哦，马可？
- Polo.
- 波罗。
[mellow music]
[柔和的音乐]
♪ ♪